ALVIN JACKSON

SENIOR UX & UI PRODUCT DESIGNER

Creating harmony between a product, a user, and a business is very essential. I am a strategist that tailors a well-documented plan to build a solution for all team members, users, and stakeholders.

Experienced in remote work and open to relocate or come in office if needed.

Address:

70 Lost Meadow Trail The Hills, TX 78738

P: 737-206-0715

E: hello@alvinjackson.com

W: www.alvinjackson.com

SKILLS & TECH



UI DESIGN

8+ yrs. creating experiences in Invison, Adobe XD & Suites, Basalmiq, Axure, Sketch and Figma.



HTML & CSS

3+ years building responsive using Visual Studio, Github, Bootstrap, Javascript, and more.



LEAD

Working with developers, designers, and stakeholders using Trello, Jira, Zoom, Skype, Slack, and Azure.



UX & RESEARCH

8 + years creating user flows, journeys, and more. Invision, Flowmapp, Overflow, Miro, Mural, and Adobe.



DEVELOP & LAUNCH

Coordinating with dev. team, finalize designs, speed test, micro details, A/B testing, and launch.



EXPERIENCE

7+ YEARS OF CREATING AND LEADING

INVENTIVE WORKS, LLC

Senior UX and UI | January 2019 - present

Assist in the creative direction of the user experience and design regarding application interface. My work is a compilation of UX strategies (flows, JTBD, and stories) which are then transitioned into UI design using Adobe XD for prototypes and style guide libraries, and Adobe suites for visual marketing and launch materials. Using Jira, Miro, Zoom, and Slack ensures strong team communication, as we take design mockups, prototypes, and development to meet aggressive deadlines for enterprise applications in an Agile environment for companies like Assurant, Prograde Digital, and Texas A&M College.

CHARLES SCHWAB

User Experience Architect/Designer | March 31, 2021 - September 2021

Responsible for delivering human-centered design, focused on complex customer activities within the financial services industry. UXAs/UXDs work alongside other agency creatives, marketing leaders, developers, content strategists, and project managers to provide unique solutions, designing patterns/components for CMS platforms, Drupal focused. Website redesign for microsites, email template designs and strategy focused, financial literacy campaigns, Perform product and user research when appropriate and bring those insights to creative partners in ways that help them engage with and deeply understand what we've learned.

VESTOR POCKET, LLC

Senior UX & UI | May 2017 - January 2019
Recent Projects | SA Shoe & Company, Livestock Loader, LLC, DebonaireU

For start-ups and other companies, I did research regarding strong data analysis, user stories, and user flows. Exploration and design then take place using wireframes, style guides, and mockups with tools Sketch, Basalmiq, Adobe XD, and Invisionapp for small companies and Start-Ups in an Agile and Scrum environment when needed. The user approved prototype and design elements are then pushed to the developers. Once the product is developed quality testing and launch are accomplished for updates. Much print work and branding in Indesign and Adobe Suites was also used I did to help the launch phase of products.

FIRST UNITED CORP.

Senior UX and UI | March 2017 - February 2018

Through an extensive marketing campaign, I created the user experience and design of websites and multiple landing pages to help bring profitable leads for all investors within the firm. I designed, implemented content, analyzed competitor web pages and websites for A/B testing, and generating a good user experience that helped bring profitable leads. The environments used were Adobe, Google Analytics (user data and testing), Invisionapp, Sketch (style guides), and Wordpress for landing pages.

MEDIAFUSION DIGITAL MEDIA PLATFORM

Lead UX and UI | September 2016 - March 2017

As lead designer, I created the user experience and interface of a Netflix style application that could easily be added to their customer's website. This project contract also entailed me creating all marketing and branded materials using Adobe Suites. Skills and technologies used: HTML, CSS, Basalmiq, Wireframe, Sketch, Invisionapp prototyping, Jira, Adobe Suites.



EXPERIENCE

7+ YEARS OF CREATING AND LEADING

HEARST

UI & UX | March 2015- April 2016

I lead many projects consisting of enterprise projects like Hearst Media that needed an in-house product that maximized profits and production. The daily work consisted of team collaboration, interviews, research, and design. Skills used: Jira, Sketch, Balsamiq, Wireframe, Invisionapp prototyping, HTML, CSS, Content Management Systems, user research, and data, Adobe Suites.

EDUCATION

Inventive Academy, LLC - Full Stack Engineering, 2019
Nielsen Norman Group - UX Conference, 2018
Devry University - BA 2006

